<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest News | The Digital Botanical Gardens Initiative</title>
    <link>https://www.dbgi.org/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.dbgi.org/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Latest News</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.dbgi.org/media/icon_hu2fb6469703408137963092c86773317f_33056_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Latest News</title>
      <link>https://www.dbgi.org/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postdoctoral researcher position - computational ecology, metabolomics and knowledge management for biodiversity research.</title>
      <link>https://www.dbgi.org/post/swiss_dbgi_km_postdoc_offer_two/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.dbgi.org/post/swiss_dbgi_km_postdoc_offer_two/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Computational Ecology Group at the University of Neuchâtel, Switzerland, is offering a postdoctoral research position ! This postdoctoral project will be carried out in close collaboration with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unifr.ch/bio/en/groups/allard/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;COMMONS Lab&lt;/a&gt; in the Department of Biology at the University of Fribourg, Switzerland. This project is framed within the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dbgi.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Botanical Gardens Initiative&lt;/a&gt; (DBGI) and the wider &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.earthmetabolome.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Earth Metabolome Initiative&lt;/a&gt; (EMI), which aim to document the chemical diversity of living systems using untargeted metabolomic data and semantic web technologies.  The candidate will integrate ecological data into this framework and explore the potential of this approach to characterize biodiversity in the landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-background&#34;&gt;Project Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dbgi.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Botanical Gardens Initiative&lt;/a&gt; (DBGI), we leverage the outstanding living plant collections of Swiss botanical gardens as artificial yet accessible biodiversity hotspots. The long term objective of this Open Science initiative is to establish robust and scalable workflows designed to characterize and document the chemodiversity of the biosphere at a global scale (see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.earthmetabolome.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Earth Metabolome Initiative&lt;/a&gt;). To achieve this, we exploit the unrivaled sensitivity and structural determination potential of mass spectrometry and the power of semantic web technologies to build a large-scale digital library capturing the wealth of chemo- and bio-diversity knowledge. This open resource will be designed to i) advance the field of life science, ii) benefit human society (e.g. drug discovery from Nature and sustainable agriculture solutions) and iii) support biodiversity conservation projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;job-description&#34;&gt;Job Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The candidate&amp;rsquo;s objective will be to identify available ecological datasets and electronic resources, in particular on plant traits and biotic interactions, as well as environmental datasets such as soils characteristics that could be linked to chemical diversity data (from raw dataset, to formatted repositories or satellite image sets). She/he will work on the establishment of appropriate data formats and structure as well as the curation and linking to relevant ontologies. This work will be carried out in close collaboration with data scientists from the Swiss Bioinformatics Institute and DBGI project developers to facilitate their integration into the current DBGI Knowledge Base. Finally, she/he will explore approaches to leverage the topology of this knowledge graph in order to highlight and elucidate ecological functions of the metabolome and ultimately develop novel functional biodiversity indices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-profile&#34;&gt;Your Profile&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are highly motivated to contribute to a project focused on describing and conserving biodiversity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You hold a PhD in ecology/bioinformatics with a strong track record of relevant experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have experience with data modeling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are interested in data visualization and you are familiar with open software projects and Open Research Data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are enthusiastic about learning and expanding your skill set in order to contribute towards the success of the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-offer&#34;&gt;We Offer:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A stimulating, friendly and supportive research environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access to state-of-the-art facilities and equipment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Opportunities for professional development and training.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;starting-date&#34;&gt;Starting Date:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between &lt;strong&gt;October and December 2023.&lt;/strong&gt; This &lt;strong&gt;1-year position&lt;/strong&gt; is fully funded by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.swissuniversities.ch/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;swissuniversities&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-apply&#34;&gt;How to Apply?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please send the following information to &lt;strong&gt;emmanuel.defossez(at)unine.ch&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;pierre-marie.allard(at)unifr.ch&lt;/strong&gt;. We are happy to answer any of your questions regarding the project !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A cover letter outlining your research experience and interests, and why you are interested in this position. (2 pages max)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curriculum vitae, including a list of publications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PhD diploma or equivalent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Names and contact information for three references.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-links&#34;&gt;Some links:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UniNe: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unine.ch/biologie/en/home.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.unine.ch/biologie/en/home.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UniFr: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unifr.ch/uni/en/portrait/about-us.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.unifr.ch/uni/en/portrait/about-us.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SIB: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sib.swiss/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.sib.swiss/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DBGI : &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dbgi.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.dbgi.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EMI : &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.earthmetabolome.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.earthmetabolome.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📂 this offer as pdf here : &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dbgi.org/files/postdoc_offer_DBGI.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.dbgi.org/files/postdoc_offer_DBGI.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postdoctoral researcher position: Knowledge Management in the Digital Botanical Gardens Initiative</title>
      <link>https://www.dbgi.org/post/swiss_dbgi_km_postdoc_offer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.dbgi.org/post/swiss_dbgi_km_postdoc_offer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A postdoctoral researcher position is available at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unifr.ch/bio/en/groups/allard/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;COMMONS Lab&lt;/a&gt; in the Department of Biology at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unifr.ch/home/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;University of Fribourg&lt;/a&gt;, Switzerland. The candidate will develop and implement computational solutions to establish and manage a Knowledge Graph documenting the chemodiversity of living systems using both untargeted metabolomics data and semantic web technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-background&#34;&gt;Project Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dbgi.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Digital Botanical Gardens Initiative&lt;/a&gt; (DBGI), we leverage the outstanding living plant collections of Swiss botanical gardens as artificial yet accessible biodiversity hotspots. The long term objective of this Open Science initiative is to establish robust and scalable workflows designed to characterize and document the chemodiversity of the biosphere at a global scale (see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.earthmetabolome.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Earth Metabolome Initiative&lt;/a&gt;). To achieve this, we exploit the unrivaled sensitivity and structural determination potential of mass spectrometry and the power of semantic web technologies to build a large-scale digital library capturing the wealth of chemo- and bio-diversity knowledge. This open resource will be designed to i) advance the field of life science, ii) benefit human society (e.g. drug discovery from Nature and sustainable agriculture solutions) and iii) support biodiversity conservation projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;job-description&#34;&gt;Job Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The objective of the candidate will be to develop and implement computational solutions for the establishment of a domain-specific knowledge graph gathering a large amount of unstructured and semi-structured data. This knowledge graph will be designed to organize chemodiversity-related data obtained during untargeted mass-spectrometry based metabolomics experiments but also a wide range of heterogeneous information related to the profiled samples (e.g., experimental metadata, phylogeny, geolocalizations, ecological traits). Special attention will be given to efficiently map and identify objects using resources such as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bioregistry.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bioregistry&lt;/a&gt;. The resulting graph will then be interfaced with relevant data and knowledge bases (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebi.ac.uk/chembl/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ChEMBL&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wikidata.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wikidata&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Pubchem&lt;/a&gt;). The candidate will work in close collaboration with data scientists from the Swiss Bioinformatics Institute for ontology engineering and the establishment of natural language processing-based interfaces to facilitate access to the data by scientists worldwide. The candidate will craft innovative interfaces to visualize and query the established knowledge base. Finally, the interest of alternative solution to the classical publication system (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://nanopub.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nanopublications&lt;/a&gt;) will be explored for the input/output of information to/from the graph and for the overall dissemination of knowledge acquired in the frame of the DBGI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-profile&#34;&gt;Your Profile&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are highly motivated to contribute to a project focused on describing and conserving biodiversity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You hold a PhD in data / computer science with a strong track record of relevant experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have experience with data modeling, semantic technologies, and Linked (Open) Data handling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are interested in data visualization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are familiar with open software projects and Open Research Data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are enthusiastic about learning and expanding your skill set in order to contribute towards the success of the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-offer&#34;&gt;We Offer:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A stimulating, friendly and supportive research environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access to state-of-the-art facilities and equipment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Opportunities for professional development and training.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;starting-date&#34;&gt;Starting Date:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;June-July 2023&lt;/strong&gt; for &lt;strong&gt;1.5 years&lt;/strong&gt;. This is a &lt;strong&gt;100% postdoc position&lt;/strong&gt;, fully funded by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.swissuniversities.ch/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;swissuniversities&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-apply&#34;&gt;How to Apply?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please send the following information to &lt;strong&gt;pierre-marie.allard(at)unifr.ch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A cover letter outlining your research experience and interests, and why you are interested in this position. (2 pages max)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curriculum vitae, including a list of publications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PhD diploma or equivalent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Names and contact information for three references.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-links&#34;&gt;Some links:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UniFr: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unifr.ch/uni/en/portrait/about-us.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.unifr.ch/uni/en/portrait/about-us.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SIB: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sib.swiss/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.sib.swiss/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DBGI : &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dbgi.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.dbgi.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EMI : &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.earthmetabolome.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.earthmetabolome.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📂 this offer as pdf here : &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dbgi.org/files/postdoctoral_researcher_position_DBGI_UniFr.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.dbgi.org/files/postdoctoral_researcher_position_DBGI_UniFr.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD position in eco-metabolomics: Investigating the ecological and evolutionary drivers of phytochemical diversity</title>
      <link>https://www.dbgi.org/post/swiss_dbgi_snf_phd_offer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.dbgi.org/post/swiss_dbgi_snf_phd_offer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Computational Ecology Group at the Institute of Biology, University of Neuchâtel, is seeking a PhD student to investigate the ecological and evolutionary drivers of phytochemical diversity by leveraging the living collection in Swiss botanical gardens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-background&#34;&gt;Project Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Computational Ecology Group at the Institute of Biology, University of Neuchâtel, is seeking a highly motivated candidate to join our team as a PhD student.  The project aims to investigate the ecological and evolutionary drivers of phytochemical diversity by leveraging the living collection in Swiss botanical gardens and the latest advances in mass spectrometry and computational eco-metabolomic. By accurately characterizing the metabolome of thousands of plant species held in living collections of botanical gardens across Switzerland and integrating phylogenetic, functional, and environmental information, the successful candidate will explore the evolutionary and ecological mechanism underlying phytochemical variation across the plant kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The candidate will develop novel molecular-informed biodiversity metrics and predictive models to map chemodiversity across the landscape. This project is integrated in the &amp;ldquo;Digital Botanic Garden Initiative&amp;rdquo; and the &amp;ldquo;Earth Metabolome initiative&amp;rdquo;, which represent global efforts to profile the metabolic content of all currently known species on our planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;qualifications&#34;&gt;Qualifications:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;•	Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in ecology, bioinformatic or related field.
•	Knowledge/interest in botany.
•	Knowledge of statistical methods commonly used in ecology.
•	Knowledge/interest in programming (machine learning - R/Python Language).
•	Communication and writing skills in English.
•	Highly motivated, passionate, and able to work independently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project requires extensive fieldwork, including the collection of thousands of plant samples across botanical gardens and along elevation gradients in the Swiss Alps. A motivation for botany and fieldwork is thus essential. Additionally, the successful candidate should also have a strong interest in metabolomics and bioinformatics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;place-of-work&#34;&gt;Place of work:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neuchâtel, Switzerland. The project in fully funded for 4 years by the Swiss National Science Foundation (SNSF)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;starting-date&#34;&gt;Starting date:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is some flexibility, but the anticipated starting date will be July 1st 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;application&#34;&gt;Application:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application should contain the following: 1) a cover letter describing yourself and your match to the above-mentioned project; 2) a CV describing your education, publications, and relevant work experience, 3) names and contact information for at least two references.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deadline for applications is May 15, 2023. Please, send all information to Emmanuel Defossez (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:emmanuel.defossez@unine.ch&#34;&gt;emmanuel.defossez@unine.ch&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📂 this offer as pdf here : &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unine.ch/files/live/sites/biologie/files/Annonces%20de%20postes/PhD_position_ecometabolomics_DBGI_EMI.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.unine.ch/files/live/sites/biologie/files/Annonces%20de%20postes/PhD_position_ecometabolomics_DBGI_EMI.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SNSF grant awarded for</title>
      <link>https://www.dbgi.org/post/snsf_grant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.dbgi.org/post/snsf_grant/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seminar in the Botanical Garden of Zurich.</title>
      <link>https://www.dbgi.org/post/2023-03-04-seminar-zurich/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.dbgi.org/post/2023-03-04-seminar-zurich/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We will present both the DBGI and EMI at the Department of Systematic and Evolutionary Botany in Zurich (16:00 Monday 06 March 2023)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks Rodrigo (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rcamaraleret.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.rcamaraleret.com/&lt;/a&gt;) for the kind invitation !
This will be the opportunity to discuss and exchange on the possible synergies between Rodrigo&amp;rsquo;s exciting INDIGENOMICS (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/R_CamaraLeret/status/1590995795800920064%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/R_CamaraLeret/status/1590995795800920064)&lt;/a&gt;, the DBGI and the EMI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Screenshot from (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/R_CamaraLeret/status/1630200265180692480&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/R_CamaraLeret/status/1630200265180692480&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Details at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.systbot.uzh.ch/en/Seminar.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.systbot.uzh.ch/en/Seminar.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.7701070&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://zenodo.org/badge/DOI/10.5281/zenodo.7701070.svg&#34; alt=&#34;DOI&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First DBGI-KM meeting !</title>
      <link>https://www.dbgi.org/post/2022-02-22-first-dbgi-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.dbgi.org/post/2022-02-22-first-dbgi-meeting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We had our first official DBGI-KM meeting this Wednesday 22nd February 2023 !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No group picture &amp;hellip; but trust us we where there !
The occasion to get the ball rolling and start thinking of the next steps.
Resume of the meeting can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dbgi.org/dendron-dbgi/notes/bjbdnlx9t9rmqt5uw39flf2/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.dbgi.org/dendron-dbgi/notes/bjbdnlx9t9rmqt5uw39flf2/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More on the DBGI-KM project soon &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>swissuniversities Open Research Data grant awarded for the Swiss DBGI-KM</title>
      <link>https://www.dbgi.org/post/swissuniversities_grant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.dbgi.org/post/swissuniversities_grant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled that our proposal &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Knowledge Management in the Swiss Digital Botanical Gardens Initiative (&lt;strong&gt;Swiss DBGI-KM&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; will be supported by a swissuniversities Open Research Data grant obtained for the Track B &amp;ldquo;Establish projects&amp;rdquo; call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project involves four partners: the COMMONS Lab at the University of Fribourg, the Computational Ecology group at the University of Neuchatel, the OpenBIS team at the Scientific IT Services at ETHZ and the Swiss Bioinformatics Institute. With the &amp;ldquo;Knowledge Management in the Swiss Digital Botanical Gardens Initiative&amp;rdquo; proposal, we are setting up a team of complementary expertises that aim at harmonizing and automating the many steps of the data life cycle in the DBGI. This initiative will be a place to establish and share with the community optimized workflows for the digitization of the chemical information of large biodiverse ensembles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will publish this research proposal in the next months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More on the ORD grants &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.swissuniversities.ch/en/topics/digitalisation/open-research-data/swiss-open-research-data-grants&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.swissuniversities.ch/en/topics/digitalisation/open-research-data/swiss-open-research-data-grants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
